Jaren, congratulations on being chosen
by the Titans.
What went into the whole process of
switching from linebacker to tight end
last year for the Sooners?
Yeah, definitely. So, I I grew up my
entire life I was an offensive player
and it was it was kind of just coming
out I was I was recruited at the college
level as more of a defensive, you know,
style player and that's what I did my
first 3 years, but you know, I kind of
got to a position in my career in my
junior year of college where I kind of
realized that that maybe defense wasn't
for me and I I basically just approached
coaches in the off-season and said,
"Hey, listen, I got the offensive
background. I'm kind of hitting a wall
in my career here on defense and you
know, I really think I might be able to
offer more to this team if if you let me
try out offense." You know, I was just I
was just trying to find a place where I
could add value to the team and you
know, be a guy that was able to lead us
towards success. So, they gave me the
opportunity to switch over in the
spring. They gave me a spring to try it
out and you know, it ended up working
out pretty well for me.
As far as your mentality on the
defensive side of the ball, taking that
to offense, what all did you kind of
take
over there to that side of the ball when
you were moved there? Yeah, I mean,
obviously playing linebacker you kind of
have a a little bit of an edge to you.
There's a little more tenacity there.
Obviously, you play the the game in an
aggressive style manner and that that's
something I like to do.
Jaren, you said you hit a wall as a
defensive player and that you, you know,
mentioning your offensive background,
you played quarterback in high school.
How did that help you make that
transition to tight end and how do you
feel like that's, you know, going to
help you as you transition to the NFL
level?
Yeah, definitely. You said obviously
playing quarterback you have a very, you
know, holistic understanding of of what
goes on in an offense, an offensive
scheme and then having that defensive
background as well in the in the system
that I was in with Coach Brent Venables.
It was a very
holistic system as well where you you
needed understanding of everything that
was going on around you and to to make
everything work. And so,
having having that that that mindset and
understanding of the whole concept of of
any given play is is really going to
help me moving forward.
And it has really helped me.
What was this whole process like for
you, kind of getting ready for the
draft, waiting for it today and then
kind of getting the call that you're
getting picked?
Yeah, definitely. I mean, obviously just
just the draft process in the spring,
you know, a pro day, combine, all that
stuff. I was just I felt incredibly
blessed to be in the position to go
through all that and then obviously
getting getting to draft day, there's
there's a lot of a lot of different
emotions going through the day and you
know, getting here towards the later
rounds is
it's a crazy thing, but I'm I'm I'm glad
that I ended up where I did and and I'm
happy to call myself a Titan.
What role do you see yourself fitting in
at your size and your speed, athleticism
profile in the NFL and what have the
Titans kind of told you about the ways
they want to use you? Yeah, definitely.
So, I I plan on walking in day one and
making an immediate impact on on special
teams in particular. You know what I
mean? Just Just with my my linebacker
background and my athletic ability and
understanding of of
you know, the game of football and being
able to use my athletic abilities to my
advantage. I'm I'm looking to be a big
contributor on special teams and then,
you know, carving out a role for myself
within the offense, you know, being a
a playmaker in that sense.
Where'd you grab the hat and how anxious
are you to get one with the new logo on
it?
Is this the old logo? Oh, it is, right.
Okay, so I guess we did like a a mass
order on Amazon. So, I need to get one
with the the new logo. So, I'm rocking
the old one for now.
So, you said you did a mass order, you
got all 32 teams and then that's that's
the Titans one you got?
Yes, sir. This is the one that came with
it.
What can you tell us maybe which I know
you lost your dad when you were young.
Can you tell us what you remember about
him, switching to wear his number and
honor him in school as well?
Yeah, definitely. So, obviously my my
dad passed away when I was when I was
younger. So,
I have I have very limited memories of
of him personally, but just growing up
and hearing the way that my family and
people around him talked about him and
and how he lived his life was just was
just something that I wanted to, you
know, model my life after and you know,
they've had nothing nothing but good
things to say about who he was as a man
and how much he appreciated and enjoyed
and and made people around him better.
You know, I've just kind of just taken
that and tried to lead my life through
that same example.